There's been a lot of type about neural networks.
关于神经网络 也有很多的种类
【翻译/字幕/时间轴：AcceptedDoge】
And perhaps some of that type is justified, given how well they're working.
考虑到它们的使用效果 有些使用起来恰到好处
【仅供学习交流使用，请勿标价售卖】
But it turns out that so
但事实表明 到目前
far, almost all the economic value created by neural networks has been through
几乎所有由神经网络创造的经济价值 本质上都离不开
one type of machine learning, called supervised learning.
一种机器学习类别 叫做监督学习
Let's see what that means, and let's go over some examples.
让我们举例看看 那是什么意思
In supervised learning, you have some input x, and
在监督学习中 你有一些输入x
you want to learn a function mapping to some output y.
以及你想学习到一个函数 来映射到一些输出y
So for example, just now we saw the housing price prediction application where
比如 我们之前提到的房价预测的例子
you input some features of a home and try to output or estimate the price y.
你只要输入有关一个房屋的一些特征 试着去输出或者估计价格y
Here are some other examples
我们举一些其它的例子
that neural networks have been applied to very effectively.
来说明神经网络已经被高效应用到其它地方
Possibly the single most lucrative application of deep learning today is
如今应用深度学习获利最多的一个领域
online advertising, maybe not the most inspiring, but certainly very lucrative,
就是在线广告 这也许不是最鼓舞人心的 但真的很赚钱
in which, by inputting information about an ad to the website it's thinking
具体就是通过在网站上输入一个广告的相关信息
of showing you, and some information about the user, neural networks have
因为也输入了用户的信息 于是它会考虑是否向你展示
gotten very good at predicting whether or not you click on an ad.
神经网络已经非常擅长于预测 你是否会点开这个广告
And by showing you and
通过向你展示
showing users the ads that you are most likely to click on, this has been
向用户展示最有可能点开的广告
an incredibly lucrative application of neural networks at multiple companies.
这就是神经网络在很多家公司 难以置信地提高获利的一种应用
Because the ability to show you ads that you're more likely to
因为有了这种向你展示 最有可能点击开的广告的能力
click on has a direct impact on the bottom
而这一点击的行为的改变会
line of some of the very large online advertising companies.
直接影响到一些大型的在线广告公司的收入
Computer vision has also made huge strides in the last several years,
计算机视觉在过去的几年里也取得了长足的进步
mostly due to deep learning.
这也多亏了深度学习
So you might input an image and want to output an index,
你可以输入一个图像 然后想输出一个索引
say from 1 to 1,000 trying to tell you if this picture,
范围从1到1000 来试着告诉你这张照片
it might be any one of, say a 1000 different images.
它可能是 比方说1000个不同的图像中的任何一个
So, you might use that for photo tagging.
所以 你可能会选择用它来给照片打标签
I think the recent progress in speech recognition has also been very exciting,
深度学习最近在语音识别方面的进步也是非常令人兴奋的
where you can now input an audio clip to a neural network, and
你现在可以将音频片段输入神经网络
have it output a text transcript.
然后让它输出文本记录
Machine translation has also made huge
strides thanks to deep learning where now
得益于深度学习 机器翻译也有很大的发展
you can have a neural network input an
English sentence and directly output say,
你可以有一个神经网络输入英语句子
a Chinese sentence.
接着输出一个中文句子
And in autonomous driving, you might input
an image, say a picture of what's in
在自动驾驶技术中 你可以输入一幅图像
front of your car as well as some
information from a radar, and
就好像一个信息雷达展示汽车前方有什么
based on that, maybe a neural network
can be trained to tell you the position
据此你可以训练一个神经网络来
of the other cars on the road.
告诉汽车在马路上面具体的位置
So this becomes a key component in autonomous driving systems.
这就是在自动驾驶系统中的一个关键成分
So a lot of the value creation through
neural networks has been through cleverly
那么深度学习系统已经可以创造如此多的价值
selecting what should be x and what should be y for
通过智能的选择 哪些作为x 哪些作为y
your particular problem, and then fitting
this supervised learning component into
来针对于你当前的问题 然后拟合监督学习部分
often a bigger system such as an autonomous vehicle.
往往是一个更大的系统 比如自动驾驶
It turns out that slightly different types of neural networks are useful for
这表明稍微不同种类的神经网络
different applications.
也是可以有效应用到不同的领域的
For example, in the real estate application that we saw in the previous
比如说 应用到我们在上一个视频提到的房地产领域
video, we use a universally standard neural network architecture, right?
我们不就使用了一个普遍标准的神经网络架构吗？
Maybe for real estate and online advertising might be a relatively
也许对于房地产和在线广告来说 可能是相对的
standard neural network, like the one that we saw.
标准一些的神经网络 正如我们之前见到的
For image applications we'll often use convolution on neural networks,
对于图像应用 我们经常在神经网络上使用卷积
often abbreviated CNN.
通常缩写为CNN
And for sequence data.
对于序列数据
So for example, audio has a temporal component, right?
例如 音频中含有时间成分
Audio is played out over time, so audio is most naturally represented
随着时间的推移 音频被播放出来 所以音频是最自然的表现
as a one-dimensional time series or
as a one-dimensional temporal sequence.
作为一维时间序列（两种英文说法）
And so for sequence data, you often use an RNN,
对于序列数据 你经常使用RNN
a recurrent neural network.
一种递归神经网络
Language, English and Chinese, the
alphabets or the words come one at a time.
语言 英语和汉语 字母表或单词 都是逐个出现的
So language is also most naturally represented as sequence data.
所以语言也是最自然的序列数据
And so more complex versions of RNNs are often used for these applications.
因此更复杂的RNNs版本经常用于这些应用
And then, for more complex applications, like autonomous driving, where you have
对于更复杂的应用 比如自动驾驶 你有
an image, that might suggest more of a CNN
convolution neural network structure and
一张图片 可能会显示更多的CNN卷积神经网络结构
radar info which is something quite different.
其中的雷达信息是完全不同的
You might end up with a more custom, or
你可能会有一个更定制的 或者
some more complex, hybrid neural network architecture.
一些更复杂的 混合的神经网络结构
So, just to be a bit more concrete about what are the standard CNN and
所以 为了更具体地说明什么是标准的CNN和
RNN architectures.
RNN结构
So in the literature you might have seen pictures like this.
在文献中你可能见过这样的图片
So that's a standard neural net.
这是一个标准的神经网络
You might have seen  pictures like this.
你可能见过这样的图片
Well this is an example of a Convolutional
Neural Network, and we'll see in
这是一个卷积神经网络的例子 我们会
a later course exactly what this picture
means and how can you implement this.
在后面的课程了解这幅图的原理和实现
But convolutional networks are often use for image data.
但卷积网络通常用于图像数据
And you might also have seen pictures like this.
你可能也会看到这样的图片
And you'll learn how to implement this in a later course.
你将在以后的课程中学习如何实现它
Recurrent neural networks are very good for
递归神经网络非常适合
this type of one-dimensional sequence
data that has maybe a temporal component.
这种一维序列 数据可能是一个时间组成部分
You might also have heard about applications of machine learning
你可能也听说过机器学习的应用
to both Structured Data and Unstructured Data.
对于结构化数据和非结构化数据
Here's what the terms mean.
下面是这些术语的含义
Structured Data means basically databases of data.
结构化数据意味着数据的基本数据库
So, for example, in housing price prediction, you might have a database or
例如 在房价预测中 你可能有一个数据库
the column that tells you the size and the number of bedrooms.
有专门的几列数据 告诉你卧室的大小和数量
So, this is structured data, or in predicting whether or not a user will
这就是结构化数据 或预测用户是否会
click on an ad, you might have information
about the user, such as the age,
点击广告 你可能会得到关于用户的信息 比如年龄
some information about the ad, and then
labels why that you're trying to predict.
以及关于广告的一些信息 然后对你的预测分类标注
So that's structured data, meaning that each of the features,
这就是结构化数据 意思是每个特征
such as size of the house, the number of bedrooms, or
比如说房屋大小 卧室数量 或者是
the age of a user, has a very well defined meaning.
一个用户的年龄 都有一个很好的定义
In contrast, unstructured data refers
to things like audio, raw audio,
相反 非结构化数据是指 比如音频 原始音频
or images where you might want to
recognize what's in the image or text.
或者你想要识别图像或文本中的内容
Here the features might be the pixel values in an image or
这里的特征可能是图像中的像素值
the individual words in a piece of text.
文本中的单个单词
Historically, it has been much harder for
从历史经验上看 这是很难的
computers to make sense of unstructured
data compared to structured data.
与结构化数据比较 去让计算机理解非结构化数据很难
And the fact the human race has evolved to be very good at understanding
但人类进化得非常善于理解
audio cues as well as images.
音频信号和图像
And then text was a more recent invention, but
文本是一个更近代的发明 但是
people are just really good at interpreting unstructured data.
人们真的很擅长解读非结构化数据
And so one of the most exciting things
about the rise of neural networks is that,
神经网络的兴起就是这样最令人兴奋的事情之一
thanks to deep learning, thanks to neural
networks, computers are now much better
多亏了深度学习和神经网络 计算机现在能更好地
at interpreting unstructured data as
well compared to just a few years ago.
解释非结构化数据 这是与几年前相比的结果
And this creates opportunities for
many new exciting applications that use
这为我们创造了机会 许多新的令人兴奋的应用被使用
speech recognition, image recognition,
natural language processing on text,
语音识别 图像识别 自然语言文字处理
much more than was possible even just two or three years ago.
甚至可能比两三年前的还要多
I think because people have a natural
empathy to understanding unstructured
因为人们天生就有本领理解非结构化数据
data, you might hear about neural
network successes on unstructured data
你可能听说了神经网络更多在媒体非结构化数据的成功
more in the media because it's just cool
when the neural network recognizes a cat.
当神经网络识别了一只猫时 那真的很酷
We all like that, and we all know what that means.
我们都知道那意味着什么
But it turns out that a lot of short term economic value that neural
但结果也表明 神经网络在许多短期经济价值的创造
networks are creating has also been on structured data,
也是基于结构化数据的
such as much better advertising systems, much better profit recommendations, and
比如更好的广告系统 更好的利润建议 还有
just a much better ability to process the giant databases that
一个更好的能力去处理巨大的数据库
many companies have to make accurate predictions from them.
许多公司不得不根据神经网络做出准确的预测
So in this course, a lot of the techniques we'll go over will apply
因此在这门课中 我们将要讨论的许多技术都将适用
to both structured data and to unstructured data.
不论是对结构化数据还是非结构化数据
For the purposes of explaining the algorithms,
为了解释算法
we will draw a little bit more on examples that use unstructured data.
我们将在使用非结构化数据的示例中多画一点图片
But as you think through applications of neural networks within your own team I
但正如你所思考的 你自己团队里的神经网络
hope you find both uses for them in both structured and unstructured data.
希望算法对于结构化和非结构化数据都有用处
So neural networks have transformed supervised learning and
神经网络已经改变了监督学习
are creating tremendous economic value.
正创造着巨大的经济价值
It turns out though, that the basic technical ideas behind neural networks
但事实证明 基本的神经网络背后的技术理念
have mostly been around, sometimes for many decades.
大部分都是离我们不遥远 有的是几十年
So why is it, then, that they're only just now taking off and working so well?
那么 为什么他们现在才刚刚起步 效果得那么好
In the next video, we'll talk about why it's only quite recently
下一集视频中 我们将讨论为什么最近的
that neural networks have become this incredibly powerful tool that you can use.
神经网络已经成为你可以使用的强大工具